Rory Hartong-Redden

October 24, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rory-hartong-redden | roryhr.com

Summary

Senior Data Scientist with 6+ years of expertise in data analysis, experimentation, and machine learning. Throughout my career I've focused on solving the right problem, understanding my data, writing great code, and being a good teammate.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, R, Shell DevOps: GitHub, AWS, Docker, CI/CD, CircleCI Data Processing: Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3, Airflow, Databricks Python Tools: pandas, scikit-learn, Flask, XGBoost, TensorFlow, PySpark, Matplotlib, Jupyter

Professional Experience

• Fast Radius (SyBridge)

Boulder, CO

Senior Data Scientist / Technical Manager

Aug 2021-May 2024

- Led a 3-person data science team, partnering with product and engineering teams to develop and deploy key products featured in our IPO documents
- Ensured API uptime of our revenue-critical service, facilitating \$10M in monthly instant quotes
- Performed time-series analysis on manufacturing IoT data to support R&D efforts
- Used SQL to extract and analyze data, monitor model performance, create dashboards, and answer business questions
- Fast Radius Chicago, IL

 Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021
 - Founding data scientist: developed, deployed, and maintained the first cost-prediction regression models, contributing to the early growth of the platform
 - Contributed to "Manufacturing and Development Platform" patent, laying the groundwork for the company's software architecture
 - Established our data science platform with Python, scikit-learn, Flask, Docker, and AWS
- runtastic Linz, Austria
 Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019
 - Designed and developed a "People You Might Know" feature using Python, Spark, and Hadoop, improving user retention
 - Built an ETL pipeline to anonymize customer data for GDPR compliance

• Allstate

Research Analyst

Menlo Park, CA

Jul 2016–Sep 2018

- Developed and trained machine learning models using Python, pandas, TensorFlow, and Spark to predict risk using customer GPS data, public crash data, and synthetic data
- Co-authored a research paper with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab: "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision"

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara

MS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA Dec 2014

• University of California, Santa Barbara
BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA June 2010